Contact

adarsh.nagesh@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/adarshjamadagni (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD)

Leadership

Aerodynamics

Certifications

MATLAB Onramp

Participated as Pravega Racing's Aerodynamic Engineer at Formula Student Germany 2019

Six Sigma and the Organization (Advanced)

MATLAB Fundamentals

Introduction to Thermodynamics: Transferring Energy from Here to There

Jamadagni Nagesh Adarsh

Chief Marketing Officer and Aerodynamics Department Lead at Pravega Racing

Tamil Nadu

Summary

I aim to make the best use of my technical experiences in the automotive domain. I am passionate about being a good leader, and every step I've taken along the way has been carefully measured to not only make the best use of my technical and leadership capabilities but to learn and absorb as much as possible from each situation. Most importantly, I want to make a difference in the world, and I believe that occupying leadership roles would enable me to do the same.

Experience

Pravega Racing 2 years 7 months

Chief Marketing Officer October 2019 - Present (11 months)

- Undertaken key initiatives to improve the effectiveness of the engineering functions and cross-functional coordination including work scheduling, process planning and cost estimation for the fabrication of a Formula Student Car worth \$40,000
- Led the 'Rulebook Team' to qualify in 4 International Formula Student Events (Netherlands, Hungary, Austria, and Czech) through their respective Rulebook Quizzes which involves questions related to the rules around which the car has to be built and general engineering knowledge.
- -Coordination with suppliers, sponsors, and internal groups to meet the quality and delivery due date of the car. Brought in sponsorship of over 9200 dollars from various companies in both the Automotive and Non Automotive Domain.

Aerodynamics Department Lead September 2019 - Present (1 year)

- Initiated and implemented systematic pre-processing and post-processing routines to make the most of the limited computational resources and ensure efficient CFD workflow.
- Implemented and oversaw the design of the rear wing with emphasis placed on the increased coefficient of lift: Coefficient of drag ratio in comparison to the previous designs followed by the design of the front wing and sidepods with emphasis placed on the coherent working of the said elements and reduced pitch sensitivity of the front wing.
- Worked closely with the Vehicle Dynamics Department to develop a Laptime simulator and an Aeromap to monitor and optimize sensitivities of the aero package. Started research and development work, involving preliminary designs into diffusers, undertray and side wings for future implementation

Aerodynamics Engineer

July 2018 - October 2019 (1 year 4 months)

Vellore Area, India

- Designed an Airfoil optimization sequence using XFLR5, SolidWorks and StarCCM+ to automate the shape optimization process for an Airfoil. Designed the front wing with a custom airfoil with the primary objective of reducing flow separation tendencies under the pitch of the car.
- Worked closely with the Composites Department to introduce foam-core, male lay-up wing element manufacturing, leading to better retrieval of leading-edge curvature and a 1.5kg loss in weight.
- Represented the Aerodynamics Department at the Design Event(An event wherein points are awarded based on the team's ability to defend their designs in front of industry professionals) of Formula Student Germany 2019, helping the team become the highest-scoring Indian team for the Design Event in the history of the competition.

Marketing Executive

February 2018 - July 2019 (1 year 6 months)

Vellore, Tamil Nadu

- Undertook the responsibility of managing the team which involved frequent communication with the university, negotiations with major suppliers and manufacturers, maintaining and building productive relationships with sponsors.

- Part of the Business Plan Presentation Team. Regularly worked on building business cases for the Business Presentation Event.
- Managed and organized a successful unveiling event for the launch of Pravega Racing's new prototype racecar.
- Co-ordinated with logistics companies, customs office, and university purchase office to manage the shipping of the prototype racecar to Australia in 2018 and Germany in 2019.
- Managed social media campaigns

Vellore Institute of Technology Student

Education

Vellore Institute of Technology
Bachelor's degree, Mechanical Engieering · (2017 - 2021)

Deeksha Center for Learning - Bangalore Pre-University College · (2015 - 2017)

Yuvabharathi International School - Singapore High School · (2012 - 2015)

Delhi Public School - Bangalore (2006 - 2012)